Kashiful Haque

 $+918240868544 \mid \underline{haque.kashiful7@gmail.com} \mid \underline{github/kashifulhaque} \mid \underline{linkedin/kashifulhaque} \mid \underline{ifkash.dev}$

Software Engineer with more than 2 years of experience in Backend Development, Data Science, AI and ML. Expertise in NER, NLP, fine-tuning LLMs, Generative AI and building RAG solutions. Studied Data Science at IIT Madras.

Work Experience

Associate Software Engineer

07/2023 - Present

Fiery (an Epson company)

Bangalore, India

- Led development of "Beacon", an innovative NLP-driven system utilizing LLMs and entity extraction for intelligent print job processing.
- Engineered automated workflow to extract print specifications from user emails, significantly streamlining the printing process and enhancing user experience.
- Built an audio fingerprinting solution to identify ads played on commercial stations like TV, etc.
- Built RAG based FieryGPT using LLaMa 3.1 8B LLM, trained LORA adapter on company data for Question and Answering.

Data Scientist, Intern 01/2023 – 07/2023

Electronics for Imaging

Bangalore, India

- Developed an innovative product mockup solution using ImageMagick, Node.js, and Python, delivering superior results compared to expensive Photoshop APIs.
- Implemented cost-effective image processing techniques, resulting in significant cost savings and improved efficiency for the company's product visualization workflow.

Fullstack Developer, Intern

07/2022 - 12/2022

Corteva Agriscience

Hyderabad, India

- Improved Flask codebase, resulting in 15% faster AutoML job triggering on Kubernetes.
- Led migration of refactoring of Flask monolith to scalable APIs, improving scalability and reduced deployment time by around 10%

Education

Indian Institute of Technology Madras

2020 - 2024

Bachelor of Science, Data Science and Applications

University of Calcutta

2016 - 2019

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communications Engineering

Projects

Boo • git repo

Python, Discord.py, Go, PostgreSQL, Cloudflare Workers, Linode

Odeer • git repo

Go, Gin, Cloudflare

Skills

- Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, C++, Rust, Go, SQL
- Node.js, Express.js, Vue, Angular, FastAPI, Flask, Tailwind
- NumPy, Pandas, scikit-learn, Pytorch, huggingface, JAX, NLTK, spaCy, CUDA
- · Vector database, Qdrant, MySQL, SQLite, Redis, Docker, Git, Linux